It's the first time I've heard someone
还是第一次
sing a nursery rhyme in a graveyard.
听见有人在墓地唱童谣
At a dark and windy night,
月黑风高
it is rather intriguing.
倒是别有一番风趣
It's you.
是你啊
You saved me.
是你救了我呀
You can take me
你可以就把我
as a mysterious man,
当作神秘人
the Maskman,
鬼面兄
a friend.
当做朋友
Lady Lu,
陆书令史
how could you come to the II
大驾光临御察司
and leave without
居然不跟来某
saying goodbye?
打个招呼就要走
Lai Luozhi
来罗织
has done so many bad deeds.
做了那么多坏事
He must have been pretending.
那一定是伪装的
He might even
说不定
have some ulterior motives
他接近我
for reaching out to me.
也是有所图谋
Excuse me.
借过
Coming through.
让一下
Poker face!
江古板
Thank you, sir,
谢谢老板
Here.
来
Try this.
快尝尝
Try it.
尝尝
What are you doing?
你在搞什么
Why are you following me?
干吗要跟着我
To... to protect you.
保 保护你啊
Protect me?
保护我
How long have you been following me?
你跟了我多久了
Not... not that long.
没 没多久
So,
所以
that's why Yun Que has been
最近徐帅身边
following Chief Xu around,
都是云雀跟着
because you have spent all your time
是因为你把时间
following me?
都花来跟我了
Not entirely.
也不全是
Yun Que...
云雀
You fool!
笨蛋啊
He is your boss.
那是你老大
So why are you following me?
你干嘛跟着我
I'm afraid you might run into danger.
我怕你遇到危险
Then you should've just told me.
那你就告诉我嘛
Why did you sneak around like a thief?
干吗要搞得跟做贼一样
You wouldn't have agreed.
你不会同意的
Sir,
老板
how much is this?
多少钱
I already paid.
我付过了
You're still
你呀
the same as when you were little,
还是跟小时候一样
always throwing around gold ingots
动不动就喜欢使金锭子
without regard for their worth.
也不看值不值得
Nonsense.
胡说
I, Lu Chuichui,
我陆垂垂
have always been very prudent
从来都是精打细算
with my spending.
不乱花钱的
How do you know that since I was little...
你怎么知道我从小
You're blushing!
你脸红了
Why are you blushing?
你怎么脸红了
You haven't even had any wontons yet.
你都没吃馄饨呢
Come with me.
跟我走
Such... Such...
这 这 这
Such a big gold ingot.
这么大一锭金子
When did you
你什么时候
become this rich?
变得这么有钱了
A man shouldn't
男子汉一辈子
spend his life serving others,
伺候人怎么行
but should do something more meaningful
要去做更有意义的事情
to help more people.
保护更多人
Little Miss.
小娘子
from now on, I'm your person.
以后我就是你的人了
From now on,
从此
I'm your person.
我便是你的人了
It was you,
是你
the poor kid who had to sell himself?
那个穷得卖自己的小子
Chuichui,
垂垂
I listened to you.
我听你的话
I worked hard and had helped
我努力帮助
many, many people.
很多很多很多人
From the moment you gave me this gold,
你给我这枚金锭子开始
I, Jiang Langxing,
我江郎行
became Lu Chuichui's person.
就是你陆垂垂的人了
Ying.
皇姐
Lord Shen.
沈大阁领
I've heard that Lord Shen
素闻沈大阁领
usually avoids such banquets.
向来不爱参加这种宴饮
I didn't expect to see you
没想到今日
come here with Lady Yan today.
竟携沈夫人一同前来
It's truly a pleasant surprise.
真是让本王惊喜之至啊
Now that Lord Shen has arrived,
沈大阁领都来了
why hasn't the equally famous
与白无常齐名的来中丞
Chancellor Lai arrived yet?
怎么还迟迟不见人影啊
I apologize for being late.
来某来迟了
As the snow is about to fall,
眼看要落雪
I wonder if Fu would have the honor
不知家姐可有幸
to join Princess Ying and the ladies
与英王和女眷们
to watch the snow.
结伴去赏雪啊
Fu.
阿姐
Lord Lai,
没想到
it is indeed a great honor for me
来中丞竟携令姐前来
to have both you and your sister here.
真是给本王十足的面子
I apologize for being late.
罗敷来迟
Please forgive me.
还请各位恕罪
Why don't you all take your seats,
不如各位就座
and I will pour wine
罗敷亲自向各位
for everyone to apologize.
斟酒赔罪
Good.
好
Take your seats.
入座
Your Highness.
贤王殿下
I apologize.
罗敷失礼
She looks so agile
她看上去如此灵活
and doesn't look like
完全不像是
she's been hurt at all.
受过伤的样子
Could it be that you
莫非你在甘南道
really mistook someone for her in Gannan?
真的认错人了
I heard that Lady Yan is very talented.
听闻沈夫人才艺双绝
Perhaps you could perform a dance
不如舞上一曲
and liven things up?
助助兴如何
She has a point.
这倒是真的
Lady Yan rarely attends such banquets.
沈夫人难得来参加宴饮
So you mustn't disappoint Prince Xian.
自然该给贤王一个面子
You didn't become too proud now
总不会因为
that you have Her Highness's favor,
如今得太皇太后赏识
did you?
就恃宠而骄了吧
Don't you think so?
大家说是不是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
是啊 是啊
Lord Zhang,
张相
I remember when you were proposing
本宫还记得你在御前
this marriage to the empress dowager,
替沈颜两家说亲时
you said that Lord Yan's daughter
说颜氏有女
is of great talent,
笔歌墨舞
and her talents
淑女之名
are well-regarded in Xiang'an.
冠绝襄安
Today offers a great opportunity.
今日有此机会
She must give us the chance
确实得让大家
to appreciate her talents.
见识一番啊
I have also heard that
本王也曾听说过
Lady Yan once amazed everyone
沈夫人曾在开阳盛会
at the Kaiyang Festival
以一曲琵琶舞
with a pipa dance.
惊艳四座
I wonder
不知今日
if you might perform a new piece
可否在我这贤王府
for us today?
再舞新曲啊
Erudite Yan's daughter
颜博士教女
must be well-versed in the Six Arts.
必定是六艺齐全
Why not grace us with your performance?
不妨给大家助助兴
My wife isn't...
夫人今日
Honey.
夫君
This is such a warm invitation.
既然如此盛情难却
Then I will happily join in the fun.
那颜幸便陪诸君一乐
Honey,
夫君
may I borrow your sword?
借剑一用
Fortunately I've been watching
幸好沈渡每日练剑
Shen Du's sword practice every day.
我都有偷偷观摩
Lord Lai,
来中丞
isn't your sister
你的姐姐
a woman of seclusion?
不是深闺女眷吗
How could she
怎么会有
have such great martial skills?
如此高强的武功啊
This stance
这身形功法
looks quite familiar.
怎么有些眼熟啊
I think...
好像
I've seen it before.
在哪见过
I apologize.
沈某得罪了
Lord Lai,
来中丞
Xing lacks skill in swordsmanship
六娘剑艺不精
and have offended your sister.
冲撞了令姐
Fortunately, your sister
也好在令姐
is exceptional at martial skills
武学造诣渊博
and I sparred a few rounds with her.
与沈某套招对打了几下
Hope I did not spoil the banquet.
不算扰了宴饮的雅兴
It's no bother.
无碍
Bravo!
精彩
The sword dance between
沈夫人
Lady Yan and Chancellor Lai's sister
来中丞的姐姐
was quite the show.
舞剑确实精彩
What a sight to behold!
让本王大饱眼福啊
You're embarrassing yourself.
丢人现眼
Go fix your attire, now.
还不快回去整理仪容
You were far too reckless just now.
你刚才胆子也太大了
But it worked, didn't it?
但有用不是吗
Now your doubts
这下你能确定
can be cleared.
心中的疑惑了吧
It was Luo Fu
甘南道遇到的
in Gannan.
就是来罗敷
Honey,
夫君
it might have looked easy,
这看起来容易
but the sword was so heavy
这剑舞起来可太沉了
that I almost
我好几次
dropped it a few times.
都要砸到地上了
Lady Yan, you're of remarkable talent, and
沈夫人才艺双绝
you two have such a loving relationship.
又与沈大阁领郎情妾意
It's really enviable.
真是叫人羡慕啊
The sword dance of Lord Shen and Lady Yan
大阁领夫妇的剑舞
was truly eye-opening.
确实让人大开眼界
But the tune
不过金乐师
that Mr. Jin just played
刚才这首曲子
seems unfamiliar.
倒好似从未听过
It's a new piece I composed
是下官为应冬至之景
for the winter solstice,
所谱的新曲
called Joy and Sorrow.
《忧欢》
Mr. Jin
金乐师
is Mother's favorite musician.
是母后最爱的乐师
It's quite hard to hear him perform.
平日里想听他演奏极难
And today at Prince Xian's banquet,
没想到今日贤王宴请
not only was he invited here to play
不但能请到金乐师
for us,
给我们演奏
he also composed a new piece for us.
还可以为我们谱写新曲
What a privilege indeed!
实在是令人羡慕啊
I didn't expect
本王也没有想到
to be able to hear
能在这宴会当中
Mr. Jing's new piece today either.
听到金乐师的新曲
It's truly a pleasant surprise.
属实是意外之喜啊
As the cold deepens, snow is near.
天寒欲雪
What an elegant banquet indeed.
如此雅致的宴饮
Everyone,
诸位
let's all raise our cups,
我们共同举杯
and thank Prince Xian for inviting us.
感谢贤王相邀
Help me...
救我
It hurts. It hurts.
好痛 好痛
Help me!
救救我
You were injured by Shen Du in Gannan,
你在甘南道为沈渡所伤
and thanks to the Western medicine
亏我重金寻来西域神药
that I spent a fortune on,
才能暂时压制住
your wounds were controlled,
你的伤口
allowing you to attend the banquet
让你今日恍若无事般
to clear your name.
出席宴会以证清白
Yet you acted recklessly
可你却一时逞勇斗狠
and had given yourself away!
露了行迹
You still can't realize your mistake?
还不知错
I'm going to kill Shen Du!
我要杀了沈渡
Now, your injuries have worsened,
你如今伤上叠伤
and you've raised everyone's suspicion.
又引得众人起疑
Recently,
最近
you can't show your face in public again.
是不能再抛头露面了
No. No.
不 不
No!
不
Give me a little time.
给我点时间
Just give me a little time.
给我一点时间
Soon.
我很快
I will recover soon.
我很快就能恢复如初
Recover?
恢复了
And make people think it was you
再让别人怀疑
who pretended to be Chen Huo'e again?
是你假扮了陈火蛾吗
Believe me.
相信我
I can still be of use.
我还有用
I can still be of use!
我还有用的
I still need to
我还要扮演好
play the role of your sister, don't I?
你来中丞的姐姐不是吗
Give me a little time.
给我点时间
Believe me.
相信我
I will get better.
我会好的
I will be good.
我会听话的
Help me.
救救我
I can still be of use.
我还有用的
It hurts!
好痛
Help me!
快救救我
Just because it didn't snow,
今年冬至没有下雪
so you are going to
是打算
turn yourself into a snowman?
把自己变成个雪人吗
I'm making jiaozi for you.
我打算包饺子给你吃
Jiaozi, look.
包饺子 你看
My lady,
夫人
the palace has sent a message again.
宫里的内官又来了
You are summoned by the Empress Dowager.
太皇太后宣召
You're going to the palace more frequently
现在你进宫的次数
than I am these days.
比我还多
Got it.
好
Then I will get changed now.
那我马上去更衣
I will finish this when I get back.
我回来再给你弄
Bye bye!
走了
Greetings, Your Highness.
微臣拜见太皇太后
Get up.
免礼
Come closer now,
近前来吧
Lady Yan.
颜爱卿
Thank you, Your Highness.
谢太皇太后
Today is the Winter Solstice,
冬至了
I have sent them all home to celebrate
我让她们过节去了
and asked only you to come here,
独独抢了你来陪哀家
you won't blame me, Lady Yan, will you?
沈爱卿不会怪我吧
Of course not, Your Highness.
太皇太后说笑了
Come.
来
Sit down.
快坐下
I heard
我听说
that Lord Lai
昨日来爱卿
made a joke
也与沈爱卿
with Lord Shen yesterday, right?
开了个玩笑是吧
Yes.
是
Both of them
他们俩
are my right-hand men.
都是我的左膀右臂
You should advise Lord Shen
你该劝解沈爱卿
to avoid any conflicts
别和来罗织
with Lai Luozhi.
生出什么嫌隙
It would be better if he just leave it be.
事情到此了了才好
Thank you, Your Highness.
承蒙太皇太后关心
Although I am unaware of the details,
微臣虽不知其中的关节
but my husband
但夫君
is devoted
一心一意
to serving Your Highness
为太皇太后做事
and would never
自然是不会生了
act with any personal bias.
偏颇私心
The snow should be falling soon.
这雪也该下了
The new year is approaching,
年关将至
and I'm another year older.
哀家又老了一岁呀
You will endure, Your Highness.
太皇太后千秋万代
It's fine.
罢了
Sit down. Sit.
快坐下 坐下
There are
这今日
no other people in the palace today,
宫殿又没什么旁人
there's no need to be so formal.
无须如此拘谨
I am
哀家也只不过是
but a mortal being.
肉身凡胎
There's no such thing as eternity.
哪来什么千秋万代啊
They respect me,
他们敬哀家
but they fear me more,
更怕哀家
for in this vast palace,
因为偌大个宫殿
no one
没有一个人
can stand beside me.
能与哀家比肩
I see that Lord Zhang
微臣瞧宝环大人
and Lady Xu holds you
还有徐内司
in high regard, Your Highness.
都待太皇太后极为尊敬
That's because I've been kind to them.
那也是哀家许下的亲厚
Your Highness,
太皇太后
you still have Princess Yong'an,
还有永安公主
and Prince Xian,
还有贤王
they are
他们都是
all your children.
太皇太后的孩子
They
他们
only have their eyes
只眼巴巴地盯着
on the
麒儿身边
position of future Regent.
那个未来的摄政王位置
They eagerly await my passing
盼着哀家早点老去
so they can seize power.
他们好大权在握
They've completely forgotten
哪还想得起
their duties as my children.
做儿女的本分呢
Okay now,
好了
enough about them.
不说他们
I summoned you today
哀家今天叫你来
because I heard
是听闻
Lord Shen had defended you fiercely.
沈爱卿对你那般维护
And it reminded me of the late Emperor.
倏然想起与先帝的日子
He also defended me like that.
先帝也是如此维护我的
He, a man
他一个一向
who always avoided conflict,
不与人为难的人
would stand against
也会为了哀家
the entire court for me.
跟满朝文武抗衡
I'm getting old.
哀家真是老了
Truly.
老了
Lately,
最近啊
I've been reminiscing a lot.
一直很爱回忆
Yan Xing,
颜幸
Lord Shen's love
沈爱卿爱你之心
for you runs deep,
是至纯至性啊
making the marriage I once decreed
反倒叫哀家当日的赐婚
seem rather presumptuous.
显得有些不知趣了
That's not true, Your Highness.
太皇太后言重了
Shen Du
沈渡心中
holds you dear,
把你看得很重啊
and it is precisely because of this
正因为如此
that I must remind you,
哀家更要嘱咐你
don't let anything cloud your judgment.
莫让乌云遮了眼
No matter what,
不管在何时何境
treasure the one who loves you truly.
要好好珍惜心上人
I will remember that.
微臣谨记
Si.
阿四
Lord Yan has asked you
郎君让您
to go back to the Yan residence.
务必回颜府一趟
My father?
爹爹
Now?
现在
Yes.
对
Please.
快上车吧
Xing,
六娘啊
come, come.
来来来
Lord Zhang has something to ask you.
张相有几句话要问你
You go ahead.
你们先聊
Lord Zhang,
张相
we just met
昨日刚在
each other at the banquet yesterday.
贤王府的宴席上见过
So why do you
不知您今日
specially come to the Yan residence
特意来颜府找我
to see me today?
是有何事
I heard that these days
听闻六娘这两日
you're often summoned to the palace
接连进宫面圣
and highly favored by the Empress Dowager.
深得圣眷垂青啊
Lord Zhang, you flatter me.
张相言重了
Her Highness
太皇太后
just wanted to chat with me,
只是找我说说话
to talk about everyday matters.
聊几句家常
To have the opportunity to chat with
能与太皇太后闲聊家常
the Empress Dowager is a rare blessing
这是多少人
that many people would never experience.
几辈子都修不来的福啊
You've survived many perils
你伴随沈渡身边
by Shen Du's side
几经生死
and now have Her Highness' favor,
现又得太皇太后的恩宠
it's truly remarkable.
实在是难得呀
Though you must be quite elated now,
如今六娘春风得意
do you still remember
可还记得
why you were asked to marry Shen Du?
为何把你嫁给沈渡啊
Today is the Winter Solstice,
今日冬至
I won't waste much more time with you.
老夫也不多与你周旋
Just tell me everything
你便将太皇太后
the Empress Dowager discussed with you,
与你讲了什么
and what had happened
还有这段时间
in Shen's Residence recently
沈府发生了什么事情
without reservation.
一一讲与本相
I don't know.
下官不知
How dare you!
你这是要反啊
Lord Zhang, you've used my father and
张相用父亲和颜府
my family to pressure me for a long time.
拿捏下官许久了
I did marry into Shen's Residence
下官确实是替三姐
in my sister's place,
嫁进了沈府
but my focus
但下官
has solely been on solving cases and
一心只在刑部审案
working diligently for Her Highness.
一心为太皇太后分忧
I don't know anything about the rest,
其他的什么都不知道
and cannot know anything.
也什么都不能知道
I hope you can understand, Lord Zhang.
还望张相乞怜
Xing,
六娘
do you think just because you have the
你觉得得到了
favor of the Empress Dowager and Shen Du,
太皇太后和沈渡的宠爱
you can act with arrogance,
便有恃无恐
and that I can't
觉得本相拿你
do anything to you
和你们颜府
or to your family?
无可奈何了吗
Imperial favor is fleeting.
皇恩瞬息变化
Shen Du is in a precarious position.
这沈渡自身难保
Do you truly believe he can protect you
你就相信他护得下你
or your family?
护得下你们颜家
I don't want to rely on anyone
六娘并不想依靠谁
but myself.
只想靠自己
Good.
好
You've grown tough,
翅膀硬了
have you?
是吧
This time,
此番
when my husband and I
六娘与夫君
went to investigate the masked spectre
一同前往甘南道
and the Fire Moth Sect
一路追查半面鬼
in Gannan,
和火蛾门
we also gathered much information
收获了很多边疆的见闻
about the border regions
也顺藤摸瓜
and uncovered
了解到了很多
many unexpected stories.
想不到的故事
Lord Zhang, would you
不知道张相
be interested in hearing one?
有没有兴趣听听
What are you trying to say?
你要说什么
Xing,
颜六娘
think before you speak!
休要信口雌黄
If you don't want to hear it, Lord Zhang,
既然张相不爱听
then I won't tell.
下官便不讲了
However, as I was
不过下官今日
reviewing the case files today,
翻阅刑部卷宗
I had a question.
心中倒有一问
Why is there no petition from you
当年沈府旧案
regarding the old case of the Shen family?
张相为何无一纸奏疏
How could you have no stance on this case?
对此大案竟毫无立场
On the public side,
为公
you were already a crucial court official.
张相当时已是朝廷肱股
On the private side,
为私
weren't you
张相不是曾与
a classmate of Shen Bingzhu?
沈秉烛大人为同窗吗
What are you trying to say?
你想说什么
What do you know?
你究竟知道些什么
I don't know anything,
下官不知道些什么
or what I should or shouldn't know.
也不知道该知道些什么
How dare you threaten me
你毫无证据
without any evidence?
就想威胁老夫
Lord Zhang, if you had any questions,
张相有什么疑问
you could have just come to my residence.
来沈府问我就是了
Don't you think it's a bit inappropriate
绕这么大一圈
to come all the way to the Yan residence
来颜府找我夫人麻烦
and bother my wife?
不合适吧
Lord Zhang, I thought
本阁领原以为
you were a paragon of integrity
张相乃是朝堂清流
and disdained the corrupt bureaucracy.
不屑于官场的腌臜行为
How is it that you've now resorted
如今怎么开始
to threatening a woman?
威胁起一介女子了
I bid you farewell.
告辞
Xing.
六娘
Mom.
阿娘
Caiwei, Yijiao, Mojie.
三姐 四姐 五哥
What are you all doing here?
你们怎么都出来了
Here.
来
Your father, that old fool,
你爹那个老东西
has no backbone.
没骨头
He only causes trouble for you.
就会害女儿
You came back for the Winter Solstice
你冬至回来
and left without even eating.
连饭都没吃上就走了
I know
娘知道
you must be feeling aggrieved.
你心里肯定受委屈了
Yeah.
是啊
Mother and your mom made steamed rice cake
母亲和姨娘为你和妹夫
and jiaozi for you and Lord Shen.
做了甑糕和饺子
They've already reheated it
为了等你们回来
several times waiting for you.
都热了好几回了
Your mom almost broke into tears
结果听到你们直接就走
when she heard you are leaving hastily.
姨娘着急得都要哭了
Mom,
阿娘
I'm sorry.
对不起
You have nothing to be sorry about.
你说什么对不起啊
It's all your father's fault.
这不都怪你爹
This is your favorite
你不是从小
since you were little.
就爱吃这个嘛
Xing, eat it
快吃吧 六妹
while it's still hot.
还热着呢
Thank you, Yijiao.
谢谢四姐
Thank you, Mojie.
谢谢五哥
Xing,
六娘
how have you been at the Shen residence?
你近日在沈府可都还好
Everything's good.
都挺好的
That's good then.
那就好
I overheard Father talking with
我那日听父亲
Mojie and Shiyuan the other day,
墨杰和韩郎叙话
and learned that the Empress Dowager
听说那太皇太后
is favoring Lai Luozhi
偏宠来罗织
and is suppressing Lord Shen.
打压沈大阁领
But she keeps summoning you every day
但又仿佛为了制衡
as if she's trying to balance this out.
日日叫你进宫伴圣
It's not that grave.
也没有那么严重了
Xing,
六娘
my advice remains the same.
娘还是那句话
If you and the White Death
你跟那个白无常
can have a peaceful
要是能夫妻和睦
and happy life together,
好好过日子
that's great.
那自然是好
But if you're constantly
但如若天天把脖子
living in fear
架在刀刃上
and danger,
提心吊胆的
it's better to return home.
那便不如回家
After all,
总归
there is always a place for you here.
颜府有你一处安置
Yeah.
是啊
Your mom might be blunt,
金姨娘说得直了些
but it's all for your own good.
但都是为了你好
No matter what,
无论如何
your happiness is the most important.
你的幸福最重要
Please don't make
切莫再为了颜家
more sacrifices for our family.
做太多的牺牲
Thank you, mom,
谢谢阿娘
and everyone,
还有哥哥姐姐们
for your concern.
对我的关心
I'm doing well now.
我现在很好
Really well.
真的很好
Then we can be at ease.
那我们就放心了
Right,
对了
since it's the Winter Solstice,
今日冬至休沐
and we have a rare day off,
难得无事
how about
不如我们
we stroll around the streets together?
一起去街上逛逛
He doesn't bite.
他又不会吃人
Then let's go.
那走
Your family cares for you deeply.
你的家人都很爱护你
Our family is very peaceful.
颜家家宅宁静
Though we might sometimes fight,
虽然偶有争执
it always comes from good intentions.
但大多发自善心
I'm not sure
也不知道
if this is my father's fortune
这到底是我爹的福气
or a blessing for us,
还是我们
his children.
兄弟姐妹的福气
It's a blessing for me.
是我的福气
My lost my parents early.
我父母早亡
What I envy most
最羡慕的
is a complete and happy family.
就是一家人齐齐整整
Actually, from the first time
其实我从第一次
I visited the Yan residence, I wondered
去颜府的时候就在想
why you were so determined
你为何会要立志
to clear injustices for everyone.
给天下人洗清冤屈
It's because you grew up happily,
原来是从小幸福安康
so your sense of justice is pure
心中正义纯粹
and untainted.
不含一丝杂质
From now on,
他们以后
they are also your family.
都是你的家人
My Lady.
夫人
Watch out.
小心
Look how tender the Chief of the IG,
人人闻之变色的大阁领
whom everyone fears,
在爱妻面前
is with his beloved wife.
原来如此铁骨柔肠啊
What were you doing
你怎么跟异良人
with the Delinquent?
一起来了
Xing,
颜六娘
you didn't know that
你不知道陆垂垂
Lu Chuichui is going to
要给我们异良人
marry a Delinquent?
当媳妇了
That's not true!
哪有
You and Jiang Langxing?
你跟江郎行
You two are together now?
你们两个在一起了
Go on and laugh at me.
你就尽情笑话我吧
Why would I laugh at you?
我为什么要笑你啊
I'm happy for you!
我替你高兴呢
You finally figured it out!
你终于开窍了
How did you realize that
你是怎么发现
Jiang Langxing liked you?
江郎行他心中有你的
I...
我
How did I realize it?
是因为什么
Because you are
自然是因为
beautiful, kind, and very smart,
你人美心善
of course.
而且聪慧过人了
Why the shyness?
还害羞了
I wanted to ask you
我还想问你
when you'll be holding the wedding.
准备什么时候办婚宴
I want to get married on the same day!
我要同你同一天嫁人
You are getting married too?
你也要嫁人
Who are you marrying?
你嫁给谁啊
Yan Xing,
颜幸
have you become foolish from
你是不是查案子
working on cases too much?
把脑子查傻了
Couldn't you tell?
这都看不出来吗
I'm marrying Xiangren, of course.
当然是嫁给徐帅了
Congratulations.
恭喜
Thank you.
多谢
Shen Du,
沈渡
I don't like you anymore.
我现在已经不喜欢你了
So from now on,
所以以后
you have to treat Xing well.
你要对六娘好一点
If you scare her away,
要是把六娘都吓跑了
no woman will ever like you again.
恐怕没有女子再喜欢你
You will never find a wife again.
你就讨不到夫人了
So what?
那又如何
Yan Xing
我沈某此生
is the only woman I want.
有颜幸一人足矣